DANIEL PITT

Senior Full Stack Engineer

@ danielpitt1027@gmail.com

Singapore, Singapore

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Engineer

Self-Freelancing

02/2020 - Present

[React.js | Next.js | Vue.js | Angular.js | TypeScript | Tailwind CSS | Node.js | Firebase | MongoDB | Laravel | WordPress | UI Design | Web3]

- Due to the pandemic, I had to transition to remote work, and I discovered that it was an exciting and efficient method of working. I thoroughly enjoyed the experience and found it to be highly productive. I always strive to build long-term professional relationships with my clients.
- My mission is to continually improve each subsequent project, surpassing the quality of the previous one. This commitment has resulted in a remarkable 70% repeat hire rate, and I have had the privilege of working with certain clients for over 7 years. This is more than just a job to me. It is my life's passion.

Full Stack Engineer

Broadlume

m 02/2019 - 06/2020

[React | Gatsby | GrapthQL | Bootstrap | UI/UX Design]

- Developed a website to introduce the flooring industry and announce conferences on flooring technology
- Revised and updated the UI/UX design based on development needs
- Implemented the UI/UX design using React Gatsby and Bootstrap
- Tracked and fixed bugs and issues using GitHub as an issue tracking board

Senior Software Engineer

Tiny Talk

= 05/2016 - 11/2018

[React | Redux | Flutter | React Native | Firebase | PostgreSQL]

- Developed several apps that allows random one-to-one or group video chats that last seven minutes.
- Implemented a server-less back-end solution using Firebase Authentication.
- Built a mobile app and implemented a complicated UI/UX design using Flutter.
- Implemented one-to-one and group video calls on the app using Agora RTC Engine.
- Implemented deep linking to channels and video calls using Firebase Dynamic Links.

SUMMARY

I am a passionate senior full stack engineer with over 10 years of experience in software engineering.

Always love challenges and hard working to achieve goals. Have advanced knowledge of multiple programming languages, frameworks and extensive familiarity with several database structures.

Working as a senior developer, lead developer, I have built several successful websites, mobile apps, and DeFi platforms for a large number of users, and have successfully completed several projects involving various technical fields depending on the business idea of the client.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Software Engineering

National University of Singapore

= 04/2008 - 03/2012

SKILLS

Flutter

Web Frontend

HTML	css	JavaScript	
JQuery	Туре	Script I	ootstrap
React	Vue	Angular	Next
Web Back	kend		
PHP	Python	Laravel	Django
NodeJS Express ASP.NET			
NodeJS	Expr	ess AS	P.NET
NodeJS Mobile Ap			P.NET

React Native

Xamarin



WORK EXPERIENCE

Mobile App Developer

Kiskoo

= 02/2015 - 04/2016

[React Native | Redux | API Integration]

- Developed several mobile apps to show instant results of all lotteries played in the United States and Latin America.
- · Integrated an API for Conectate Sports to get lottery data.
- Developed mobile apps and implemented complicated UI and UX with React Native, Redux, and Redux Thunk.
- Implemented banner, reward, and interstitial ads using Google AdMob.

Full Stack Developer

Kiskoo

= 2013 - 02/2015

[HTML | CSS | JavaScript | Bootstrap | PHP | WordPress | Laravel | React | Jira]

- Developed a website to satisfy the needs of different sectors of the Dominican market including the movie music technology automotive sports tourism fashion and other industries.
- Tracked and fixed bugs and issues using Jira a reporting tool.
- Developed several subdomains using WordPress CakePHP, React, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap.
- Implemented search engine optimization using Google Tag Manager and Ahrefs.
- Implemented banner, interstitial, and reward ads using Google Ads.

SKILLS

DB, Could Services

MySQL SQLite MongoDB

PostgreSQL AWS Google Maps

Firebase Twilio

UI/UX Design

Figma Adobe XD Photoshop